A Finding Aid to the Sherman E. Lee Papers, 1947-1997, in the Archives of American Art aaa.leeshere
Archives of American Art
Sherman E. Lee papers
1947-1997
aaa.leeshere
Archives of American Art
10.3 Linear feet
The papers of Cleveland museum director and art historian Sherman E. Lee measure 10.3 linear feet and date from 1947-1997. The records document Lee’s extensive career as an art historian, curator and expert on Asian art, director of the Cleveland Museum of Art, writer, educator, and consultant. His papers include scattered biographical materials, correspondence, writings, travel files, committees and organizations files, consulting files, teaching files, personal business records, printed material, photographs, and one pencil drawing.
Lee, Sherman E.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Conract Reference Services for more information.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Cleveland museum director and art historian Sherman E. Lee measure 10.3 linear feet and date from 1947-1997. The records document Lee’s extensive career as an art historian, curator and expert on Asian art, director of the Cleveland Museum of Art, writer, educator, and consultant. His papers include scattered biographical materials, correspondence, writings, travel files, committees and organizations files, consulting files, teaching files, personal business records, printed material, photographs, and one pencil drawing.
Correspondence is with friends, scholars, editors, collectors, dealers, art societies and organizations, and other museums. Writings consist of articles, lectures, book reviews by Lee and scattered writings by others. Writing project files contain correspondence with publishers, contracts, and printed material relating to the publication of Lee's writings. Travel files document numerous trips to Asian and European countries and include travel diaries, photographs, and lists of works of art viewed. There are files concerning Lee's membership and involvement with various committees, museums, and arts organizations. Consulting files mostly focus on Lee's work advising John D. Rockefeller III on the purchase of art, and with the Permanent Public Areas Advisory Committee of Cleveland, Ohio. Teaching files document classes he taught at Case Western Reserve and Harvard. Personal business records mostly concern Lee's personal art collection. Also found among the papers are general clippings, photographs of Lee and of artwork, and one pencil drawing.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Sherman E. Lee donated his papers to the Archives of American Art in 1997.
Biographical/Historical note
Sherman Emery Lee (1918-2008) was an recognized expert on Asian art and director of the Cleveland Museum of Art from 1958-1983.
Born in Seattle, Washington in 1918, Sherman E. Lee grew up in New York and received degrees from American University and a Ph.D. from Case Western Reserve University in Cleveland, Ohio. Lee began his art career as a curator at the Detroit Institute of Art and Seattle Art Museum. During World War II, he served with the U. S. Navy and was transferred to the Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Section in Japan. After the war he continued working as a civilian advisor on the preservation of Japanese artworks.
Sherman Lee accepted a position as curator of Oriental art at the Cleveland Museum of Art in 1952 and became director in 1958, where he remained until 1983. During his long tenure there, he built one of this country's most remarkable collections of Asian art, transforming the museum from a regional presence to one of national significance. In 1973 Lee was chosen as Chairman of the Art and Archeology Delegation to the People's Republic of China, jointly sponsored by the Committee on Scholarly Communication of the People's Republic of China and the Scientific and Technical Association of the People's Republic of China.
Lee wrote or co-wrote a number of books including A History of Far Eastern Art (1964) and numerous articles for journals, magazines, and newspapers. He was the recipient of many honorary degrees, awards, and honors including the Order of the Sacred Treasure from Japan and Chevalier of the Legion d’Honneur. He taught art history courses at the Case Western Reserve University and Harvard and was consultant to John D. Rockefeller III and the Cleveland Permanent Public Advisory Committee. He retired to North Carolina where he taught at the University of North Carolina and was advisor to the University's Ackland Art Museum.
Lee was married to his wife Ruth for sixty-nine years. The two met in college and had three daughters and one son. Lee died July 9, 2008 at Chapel Hill, North Carolina.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 12 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1947-circa 1983 (0.4 linear feet; Box 1, 11)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1953-1996 (1.5 linear feet; Box 1-2)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1962-1983 (1.7 linear feet; Box 2-4)
Series 4: Writing Project Files, 1958-1997 (1.0 linear feet; Box 4-5)
Series 5: Travel Files, 1959-1994 (1.8 linear feet; Box 5-7)
Series 6: Committees and Organization Files, 1971-1997 (1.8 linear feet; Box 7-8)
Series 7: Consulting Files, 1960-1993 (1.1 linear feet; Box 8-9)
Series 8: Teaching Files, 1963-1977 (0.1 linear feet; Box 9)
Series 9: Personal Business Records, 1958-1995 (0.3 linear feet; Box 9)
Series 10: Printed Material, 1962-1987 (0.9 linear feet; Box 10-11)
Series 11: Photographs, circa 1952-1993 (0.2 linear feet; Box 10-11)
Series 12: Artwork, circa 1960s (1 folder; Box 10)
Case Western Reserve University. -- Faculty; Cleveland Museum of Art.; Harvard University. -- Faculty; Rockefeller, John D., 1906-; Art historians--Ohio--Cleveland; Art museum curators--Ohio--Cleveland; Art, Asian; Art, Chinese; Art, East Asian; Art, Japanese; Art--Study and teaching; Drawings; Educators--Ohio--Cleveland; Museum directors--Ohio--Cleveland; Painting, Chinese; Photographs; Travel diaries
- Biographical Material, 1947-circa 1983; Series 1; 0.4 Linear feet Boxes 1, 11
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of awards, scattered biographical sketches and resumes, invitations, material from Lee's service with the Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Division, retirement memorabilia, and a file of clippings and photocopies of passages entitled "useful quotations" by Lee. Awards include certificates and honorary degrees from institutions and organizations throughout Ohio and the U.S.. Retirement memorabilia consists of a goodbye collage signed by staff of the Cleveland Museum of Art and a file of printed material, photos, and notes from Lee's bulletin board.
  - Awards and Certificates, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Biographical Sketches and Resumes, 1970-circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Invitations, 1965, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives Division Material, 1947, circa 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Retirement Memorabilia, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Useful Quotations File, 1962-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Awards and Certificates, 1950s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1953-1996; Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Correspondence is with museums, colleagues and organizations. Many letters include enclosures including reports, articles, booklets, clippings, and photographs. Subjects include writing projects, travel, art and art history, consulting, organization memberships and participation in meetings and symposia.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1978-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 1957-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A, 1960-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Arts and Artifacts Indemnity, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - B, 1960-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brazillier, George, 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - C, 1952-1997 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Clark, Charles M., 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Crawford, John M., 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Crosby, Sumner McK., 1960-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - D, 1961-1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Der Religion in Geschichte und Gegenwart, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - E, 1967-1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Encyclopedia Universale Dell'Arte, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - F, 1952-1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fishing Rights Action, Canada, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - G, 1995; 1966-1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - H, 1963-1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - I, 1960-1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Instituto per la Collaborazione Culturale, Encyclopedia of the World, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - J, 1960-1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - K, 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - L, 1956-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - M, 1960-1997 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Masuda, Yoshinobu, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - N, 1966-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - North Carolina Museum of Art, Study Committee, 1972-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - O, 1962-1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Oberlin College, 1963-1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - P, 1968-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Powers, John G., 1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - R, 1958-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rocks, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rogers, Howard, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rorimer, Mrs. James (Kay), 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Royal Society for the Encouragement of the Arts, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - S, 1963-1996 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Seattle Art Museum, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Soper, Alexander, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - T, 1960-1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tyler, Susan, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - U, 1958-1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - U.S.S.R., The State Hermitage, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - V, 1959-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - W, 1958-1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - White House, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Williams College, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - X, Y, Z, 1961-1996 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Yale University, 1966-1968, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
  - Yampolsky, Philip, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Writings and Notes, 1962-1983; Series 3; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 2-4
  Writings by Sherman Lee include articles, books, essays, lectures, and reviews. Some lecture files only contain slide lists.
  Arrangement note
  Material is arranged in chronological order by type of writing.
  - Articles, Books, and Essays (Box 2)
    - "Old Man Painting by Rembrandt", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Varieties of Portraiture in Chinese and Japanese Art", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - "Japanese Decorative Style" and "Connoisseur", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - "Scattered Pearls Beyond the Ocean: Chinese Album Paintings", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - "The Art Museum and Antiquity", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "Mughal Art, Principally Painting, In New York", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "The Idea of an Art Museum", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "Tea Taste in Japanese Art", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Introduction, Exhibition Catalog, Smithsonian Institution, Indian Painting, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - "Portrait of the Jester by Velasquez", 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Articles, Books, and Essays (Box 3)
    - "Painting" and "Quality in Painting", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Preface, Ancient Cambodian Sculpture, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "The Water and the Moon in Chinese and Modern Painting", 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Forward, for Feininger, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Sosetsu and Flowers", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "To See Big Within Small: Hsiao-Chung-Chien-Ta", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "General Introduction to Cleveland Museum of Art, Oriental Objects", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Chinese Ceramics at Kansas City", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Preface, Korean Art, by Chewon Kim, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "The Tombs of Prince Liu and Princess Tu", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Two Cheers for Irrelevance" (Milton Fox Memorial), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "The Art Museum as a Wilderness Area", 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Forward, The Way of Tea by Rand Castile, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Forward, Indian Paintings from the Punjab Hills, by W.G. Archer, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - The Colours of Ink, for Asia House Exhibition, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Introduction, for Shimmel Catalog, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Noh: Masks and Robes", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Ideology and Archaeology", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "Collecting and the Seven Deadly Sins", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "Art Against Things", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Art Museums and Education", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Varieties of Portraiture in Chinese and Japanese Art", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "American Appreciation of East Asian Art", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Forward, "Public Monuments", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Article for Heibonsha, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "Horse Racing at Kamo Shrine", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Preface, Six Persimmons by David Bershtein, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Preface, Catalog by Yosiko Miwa, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "The Genius of Japanese Design", 1979 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "5,000 Years of Korean Art", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Bronze Age of China", 1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "The Nature and Significance of the Collection of Liang Ching-Piao", 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Preface, 1,000 Years of Japanese Art, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "Eight Dynasties of Chinese Painting", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller III Collection", 1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "Museum Education", 1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "Article for Connaissance des Arts", 1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - on Richard E. Fuller, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "For Yomiuri News", 1983 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "The Permanent Collection of the Art Museum", 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "Reflections of Reality", 1983 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lectures and Talks (Box 3)
    - Chinese Art, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
    - Indian Art, circa 1958-1983 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Japanese Art, 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous Art, 1958-1973 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - "Distant Past", circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - "The Connoisseurship of Chinese Paintings," Yale University, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "The Two Chinas: The Westerner's Idea and Actuality," Williamsburg, Virginia, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - "The Special (Loan) Exhibition," College Art Association, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - "Two Cheers for Irrelevance," Case Western Reserve University, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - "Eye Object," Cleveland Institute of Art, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - "Tea Taste in Japanese Art" and "Radical Change in Chinese Painting," University Center of Virginia, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "Tea Taste in Japanese Art," Asia Society, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - "Collecting, the Pleasant Disease," Atlanta, Georgia, 1972-1978 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - "Sculpture in Thailand", 1973 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - "New Arrangement of Galleries," Cleveland Museum of Art, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - "Art: East and West," Hiram College, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - "Art Museums: International, National, and Local Issues," City Club, Cleveland, Ohio, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - "Art and Archaeology in China," Baltimore Museum and Smith College, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Talk, Print Club, Cleveland, Ohio, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - "Masterworks from Oriental Art Collection," Oberlin College, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - "Art and Archaeology in the People's Republic of China," University of Wisconsin, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Lecture, Chinese Exhibition, Cleveland Museum of Art, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - "Decorative Style and Realism in Japanese Painting," University of Virginia, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - "Nature and Art: Chinese and Japanese Gardens and Paintings," Freer Gallery, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Lecture, Associated Council of the Arts, Cleveland, Ohio, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - "The Essential Museum," North Carolina Art Society, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - "Past and Present: the Dilemma of the Art Museum in China and the West", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Tokyo Masterpieces, East and West", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - "World of Decorated Screen Painting," Junior Council Lecture Series, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Lecture, Chinese Painting, Birmingham, Alabama, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - "Who Needs a Public Monument?" Cleveland Museum of Art, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - "Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of ... What?" College Art Association, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - "The Characteristics of Japanese Art and Their Relevance Today," Japan Foundation, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - "The Art Museum as Educators," City Club, Cleveland, Ohio, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Lectures and Talks (Box 4)
    - "Sanctuary," Kenyon College, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "Art and Archaeology of the People's Republic of China," Marietta College, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Connoisseurship", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Quality in the Visual Arts," Natural History Museum, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "1978 Year in Review", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Art Museums and the Problems Representative of China: Form and Contents," University of Chicago, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Statistics on Museums in China," Chicago, Illinois, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Public Monuments," Youngstown, Ohio, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "River Village, Fisherman's Joy," Cleveland Museum of Art, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "Animals in Chinese Art," Natural History Museum, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "The Double Virtue of Transmission -- China, Korea, and Japan," Junior Council Lecture Series, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Lecture, Korean Art, Junior Council Lecture Series, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Convocation Address, University of Notre Dame, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Lecture, Chinese Painting, Kansas City, Missouri, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Lecture, San Antonio Art Museum Symposium, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "The Sins and Virtues of Collecting," Kimball Art Museum, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "1961-1981 at the Cleveland Museum of Art," Gallery Group of the Cleveland Museum of Art (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "A Popular Tradition of Early Chinese Ceramics," Cleveland Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Collecting and the Seven Deadly Sins," Friends of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Collecting of Chinese Paintings," Asia Society, New York City, New York, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Water, Trees, and Rocks: Chinese Painting 1350-1650," Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Speech, Art Dealers Association Awards, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
    - "Archaeology and Historic Preservation," Jefferson Lecture Symposium, National Endowment for the Humanities, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Talk, Donor's Reception, Cleveland Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "Ceramics: A Primeval Art," Cleveland Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "In Retrospect," Harvard Business School, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "The Sins and Virtues of Collecting," Center for Fine Arts, Miami, Florida, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - "Introduction to Drawings, Old and New," Cleveland Museum of Art, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "The Meaning of the Mean," Case Western Reserve University, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - "Emaki: Well Told Tales", 1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Book Reviews, 1958-1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Notes, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - TV Script, NBC Knowledge Series, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Lists of Works of Art, circa 1947-1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Writings by Others, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 37-39)
- Writing Project Files, 1958-1997; Series 4; 1 Linear feet Boxes 4-5
  This series consists of correspondence, contracts, and financial records concerning Sherman Lee's writings for various publications and organizations. Researchers should note that the actual writings are found within the writings and notes series.
  - Article, Artibus Asiae, 1958-1972 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Catalog, Asia Society, 1958-1980 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - "Tea Taste in Japan," Arts Magazine, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - "The Idea of an Art Museum," Oberlin College, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - History of Far Eastern Art, 1964-1982 (Box 4, Folder 44-46)
  - "Portrait of the Jester by Velasquez," Bulletin of the Cleveland Museum of Art, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - "The Concept of Art Forgery," International Academy of Law and Science, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - "The Art Museum in Today's Society," Art News, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - "Painting," Quality, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - "The Water and the Moon in Chinese and Modern Painting," Art International, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "Two Cheers for Irrelevance," Case Western Reserve University, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - "The Art Museum as a Wilderness Area," Museum News, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Preface, Korean Art by Chewon Kim, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Milton Fox Memorial Essay, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - "The Tombs of Prince Liu and Princess Tu," Sunday Times, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - "Eye Object," Cleveland Institute of Art, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - "Tea Taste in Japanese Ceramics," Seattle, Washington, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - "The Holy House of Nazareth by Francisco de Zubaran," for A.D. For the Year of Our Lord, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Forward, Indian Paintings from the Punjab Hills by W.G. Archer, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - "Art and Archaeology in China Today," Baltimore Museum of Art and Smith College, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - "Art Museums: International, National and Local Issues," City Club, Cleveland, Ohio, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Article, Art International, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - "Art: East and West," Hiram College, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Remarks, Skowegan School of Painting and Sculpture Awards, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - "Masterworks from Oriental Art Collection," Oberlin College, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - "Decorative Style and Realism in Japanese Painting," University of Virginia, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Lecture, National Endowment for the Humanities, Jefferson Lectures, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - "Past and Present: the Dilemma of the Art Museum in China and the West," Portland, Maine, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - "The Essential Museum," North Carolina Art Society, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - "Ideology and Archaeology," New York Times, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Remarks, Council of the Arts, Cleveland, Ohio, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - "Nature and Art: Chinese and Japanese Gardens and Paintings," Freer Gallery and Seattle Museum of Art, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - TV Script, NBC's Knowledge Series, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - "Art Museums and Education," Council on Museums and Education in the Visual Arts, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - "Art Against Things," Art Association of Australia, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - "Collecting and the Seven Deadly Sins," Western Reserve Antique Show Exhibition Catalog, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Article, Heibonsha Limited, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - "Pablo Picasso by Pierre Cabanne," The New Republic, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - "American Appreciation of East Asian Art," United States Information Agency, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - "Live, Liberty and the Pursuit of ... What?" College Art Association, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - "Sanctuary," Kenyon College, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Preface, Six Persimmons by David Bershtein, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - "Characteristics of Japanese Art and Their Relevance Today," Japan Foundation, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - "Art and Archaeology of the People's Republic of China," Marietta College, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 85)